Email: tuta.andrei96@gmail.com http://www.github.com/andreituta Mobile: +40725565620

Career Profile

A passionate Software Developer with extensive and diversified experience in developing mobile applications, websites, web applications and offering administration services for local businesses.

Knowledge of product-life-cycle management, business development and leading cross-functional teams was gained while managing various other projects and business ideas, focusing on understanding existing and emerging technologies, Software as a Service (SaaS), while minimizing their cost and administering workload.

EDUCATION

Assistant

• Birmingham City University

Birmingham, UK

B.Sc. in Computer Science - Data Analysis. Machine Learning and Database administration

2015 - 2018

• Universidad de Alcala

Alcala de Henares, Spain

B.Sc. in Computer Science, Erasmus semester in Spain

Jan - Jun 2017

Professional experience

• Birmingham City University

Birmingham, UK

Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

- o Java demonstrator: Helped groups of students during their laboratory sessions. Tasks involved explaining concepts and helping with debugging their projects.
- o Innovation Fest Mentor: Managed and helped two teams of students with the technical development, planning and pitching of their entries for a local technology contest.

• Oracle Romania

Bucharest, RO

 $Junior\ Database\ Administrator$

Jun 2018 - Sep 2018

- o Oracle DBA training: Part of the internship consisted of a training similar to a complete DBA course. During this training, topics such as basic administration, back-up, recovery and automation were covered
- Administrator: After the training was completed, I completely installed and automated two separate databases to execute all the required procedures.

• Logika IT Solutions

Bucharest, RO

Junior Database Administrator

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

• Internship: Worked in a team of 4 people managing the databases of multiple clients. Other responsibilities included writing reports and suggestions on ways to improve the work-flow and diminish cost.

Programming Skills

• Languages: Python, Java, Javascript, Kotlin, SQL Technologies: AWS, React, Android Studio, MongoDB

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

• Outward Mobility Ambassador, BCU CEBE

Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

Recruiting students for international programs and social media development

• President, BCU RoSoc

2016 - 2018

Event planning, budgeting & team management

• Secretary, Rotaract Club Birmingham

2015 - 2017

Event planning, PR & note-taking